# FIONA PATTISON

(+44) 7515 391814



pattison.fiona@gmail.com



fpattison.co.uk



fiona-pattison-22316127



Sussex



# **EDUCATION**

Geography, BA University of Sheffield 2003 - 2006

# **QUALIFICATIONS**

Diploma in Direct & Digital

Marketing
Institute of Direct Marketing

2011

### **REFERENCES**

Available on request

### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Experienced and passionate fundraising, campaigning & brand strategist. Trusted by clients and colleagues to deliver results and smash fundraising targets in response to a wide range of briefs and challenges.

A track record of being at the leading edge of innovation, and widely recognised for launching mobile fundraising in the UK, US and Australia.

Working with many of the top UK and US charities has resulted in the development of a breadth of skills including delivering campaign strategies & budgets, pitching, audience profiling, data analysis, client servicing, business planning, product development and project management.

A problem solver by nature, I can flex my style to the task at hand and equally love working under pressure and approaching something for the first time.

A thought leader in the third sector and confident public speaker. I regularly appear at leading sector conferences, focusing in particular on how innovation and diversity are critical for future prosperity.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

FUNDRAISING STRATEGIST & PROJECT MANAGER Self employed | August 2019 - present

- Working directly with clients and in partnership with agencies to deliver fundraising strategy, digital mobilisation campaigns and organisational reviews
- Project lead on insight, creative development, results analysis, optimisation and review
- Senior client lead and project manager for international non-profit virtual events company

#### **SENIOR PLANNER**

GOOD Agency | December 2018 - August 2019

- Responsible for delivering high quality, effective and actionable insight and strategy to clients
- Working across audiences, channel & products
- Creating audience strategies for top UK charities
- Lead Planner on new business pitches
- Collaborating with Client Services to develop client plans and stretched income targets

### EXPERIENCE CONT.

#### SENIOR STRATEGIST

Open Creates | January 2018 - November 2018

- Delivering campaigns designed to deliver insight on innovative fundraising methodology
- Leading the process with account teams and clients to ensure briefs going into the department deliver exceptional work
- Working with senior colleagues across the agency to improve business effectiveness and profitability
- Driving new business into the agency
- Representing the agency by speaking at sector and industry events such as the IOF Convention

#### **ACCOUNT DIRECTOR**

Open Creates | May 2015 - December 2017

- Delivering top-level client servicing and growing the value of the agency's clients in the following areas new business, mobile & digital, international
- Writing and presenting fundraising proposals and plans
- Joint responsibility for developing the new business strategy, including pitch responses
- Creating the sales strategy of sister company Open America
- Developing and delivering annual sales budgets
- Project managed the delivery of a Facebook telethon for the ACLU
- Managing a team of Account Manager and Account Executive
- An active member of the agency Management Team and internal digital workstream

#### SENIOR ACCOUNT MANAGER/ACCOUNT MANAGER

Open Creates | November 2011 - April 2015

- Driving the creation and growth of Open's partner company Open Mobile Global
- Managing all clients using mobile (SMS/PSMS/regular giving by mobile) in their fundraising programmes in the UK, Australia and US
- Shaping and delivering analysis and reporting of mobile campaigns to clients and partner
- Central to the product development of the agency's mobile products Managing partners and industry bodies to deliver a seamless experience for clients
- The point of knowledge for Account Teams, Studio and Planning to ensure every agency client maximised the potential presented by mobile

## DIRECT MARKETING OFFICER, ACQUISITION

Unicef UK | September 2008 - October 2011

- Managing fundraising campaigns across multiple channels
- Planning, re-forecasting and reporting on income and expenditure budgets
- Contributing to the development of strategies, budgets and business plans to generate long term and sustainable income

# SENIOR FUNDRAISING MANAGER (VOLUNTEER ROLE)

Pride in London | April 2017 - April 2018

• Developing and launching Pride in London's first individual giving fundraising strategy, with a focus on identifying the best audiences and channels